Zameer Shaik

SKILLS

Java/JEE (Expert)

Problem Solving (Expert)

Oracle DB (Expert)

Shell Scripting (Advanced)

Angular/Bootstrap (Expert)

Javascript (Advanced)

HTML5/CSS3 (Expert)

STRENGTHS

- Disciplined and Hard working
- Proven Leadership skills
- Technology savvy
- Strong Communication Skills
- Excellent decision-making skills
- Excellent troubleshooting skills
- Result Oriented

ADDRESS

F#: 303, Yaam Residency, Brindavan Colony, Tolichowki, Hyderabad, India - 500008

EMAIL

techie.zameer@gmail.com

PHONE

+91 996-300-7601

Linkedin

abdul-zameer-shaik

ABOUT ME

Engineer with 11+ years of experience building software solutions to startups and Fortune 500 enterprises. I've built software from scratch and take pride in adding value by shipping well architected, high quality software in least amount of time. Have good domain knowledge of Payroll, Telecom and Digital Marketing domains.

EXPERIENCE

Oracle Corporation / Senior Member of Technical Staff

May 2016 - PRESENT, Hyderabad, India

Primary developer of Oracle UIM, Oracle's inventory product for Telecom domain.

ADP LLC / Technology Consultant

December 2010 - April 2016, Hyderabad, India

Principle developer and Lead of the ADP Datacloud, the Big Data platform that powers reporting for all ADP clients.

Designed the ETL pipeline that transformed data from multiple products into data hub for analytics

Senior developer of the team and have built ADP's payroll product for SMEs

Zeta Interactive / Senior Software Engineer

May 2007 - September 2010, Hyderabad, India

Architected and built integration services around core product Zetamail.

Built internal reporting tool to log and report metrics around emails campaigns

EDUCATION

Nagarjuna University / Masters of Computer Applications

September 2004 - May 2007, India

Academic topper in 3 out of 6 semesters

JNV University / Bachelor of Science

August 2001 - May 2004, India

AWARDS

Awarded "Associate of the Quarter" and "Best employee of the Month" multiple times in ADP. Awarded "Employee of the Month" 2 times in Zeta Interactive.

CERTIFICATIONS

Oracle Certified Java Programmer

Oracle Certified Web Component Developer

Oracle Project Summary

Project Name: Unified Inventory Management (UIM) Duration: May 2016 to till Date

Role: Senior Member of Technical Staff

Project Description:

Unified Inventory Management (UIM) is a telecom inventory management application which helps in managing and modelling of customers, resources, services. It provides life-cycle management of resources. This application is flexible that it can replace existing inventory management systems or can work cooperatively with them. It has patterns for functionalities like life-cycle management of resources, services, consumption pattern, etc. Highly scalable application.

Tech Stack: Java, ADF, JPA, SOAP, REST, Oracle SQL, PL/SQL, WebLogic, Jenkins, SVN

Contributions:

- Interact with the stake-holders to gather requirement and then design accordingly.
- Have implemented new functionalities and have exposed them in the form of webservices (SOAP and REST).
- Contributed to the product installation framework.
- Interact with customers in debugging issues and providing resolution to them.

Client: Major telecom domain clients

ADP Projects Summary

Project Name: ADP DataCloud Duration: Sep 2015 to Apr 2016

Role: Technology Consultant

Project Description:

- Big data platform providing analytical solutions to ADP customers.
- Analyzing new metrics what could be suitable for clients and then work on developing them.
- Working as development lead taking responsibilities of analyzing the product requirements and providing best solution possible.

Tech Stack: Java EE, AngularJS, JQuery, Bootstrap, REST Web services, Oracle, WebSphere, Git

Contributions/Responsibilities:

- Developed the UI framework and REST clients
- Distributing the tasks to team members and reviewing their work.
- Requirements discussion with scrum master and product owner.
- Unit Testing.

Client: Tightly integrated with all major ADP HCM products.

Project Name: TS2RUN ETL Tool Duration: May 2013 to Sep 2015

Role: Technology Consultant

Project Description:

- As company came up with an initiative of having only one product per business line so this product was developed for migrating all the clients from one product to another ADP product
- During the initial phase, we did extensive analysis for understanding the source and destination products.
- Once analyzing all the details, we then proceeded with the design phase.
- We decided to use all the latest technologies while building this product like AngularJS, JQuery, REST Web services,
 Spring and hibernate.
- Worked as Module lead for UI and REST layer.

Tech Stack: Java EE, AngularJS, Bootstrap, JQuery, REST Web services, Spring, Hibernate, WebSphere

Responsibilities:

- Analyzing requirements.
- Coding the core modules of this product.
- Involved in bug fixing and production support.
- Unit Testing.

Client: Used internally for migrating clients from one payroll system to another payroll system

Project Name: EasyPayNet Duration: Dec 2010 to Apr 2013

Role: Senior Software Engineer

Project Description:

- EasyPayNet makes payroll EASY. This is meant for serving the clients whose employee count ranges from 1-50. Around 120,000 clients are using EasyPayNet application in USA.
- This is a web interface application accessed by customers.
- EasyPayNet process is to send the payroll information via the Internet to ADP Small Business Services. Once the information is received, ADP calculates the payroll, including deductions and withholdings for all relevant tax jurisdictions, and delivers the checks, pay vouchers and payroll reports directly to the concerned business.
- The payroll reports will also be available online, as are copies of the checks and pay vouchers. Checks can also be printed directly from the users business if they prefer.
- This is a Product of ADP for Payroll calculation, and currently this is only to cater the needs of the clients in USA.

Tech Stack: Java EE, JDBC, Spring, JavaScript, HTML, Shell Script, JBoss

Responsibilities:

- Analyzing requirements.
- Coding the core modules of this product.
- Involved in bug fixing and production support.
- Unit Testing.

Client: Used by SBS clients

Zeta Interactive Project Summary

Project Name: Zeta Smart Duration: June 09 to Sep 2010

Role: Senior Software Engineer

Project Description:

Developing custom product that interacts with core product Zetamail, This product is designed to make the email campaign specific requirement gathering from Clients for email campaigns easy. Client can upload campaign related all assets here, also it is capable of displaying comparative email campaign summary between different campaigns, which makes it easier for client to have a look at any particular campaign's performance and to analyse their future strategies.

Tech Stack: Java, JDBC, Servlets, JSP, Struts and JavaScript

Responsibilities:

- Analyzing requirements.
- Coding the core modules of this product.
- Involved in bug fixing and support.
- Unit Testing.

Client: Used for all clients

Project Name: Datran Email Campaign Publish **Duration:** March 09 to June 09

Automation

Role: Software Engineer

Project Description:

Datran client is into publishing huge number of email campaigns on daily basis. Client places files having a specific naming convention on their sftp site. The program downloads and process these files to build list in eBizmailerTM(Core Product). After the list is successfully processed the list was associated to its respective campaign, and later it published automatically.

Tech Stack: Java, JDBC, JavaScript, HTML and Shell scripting

Responsibilities:

- Participated in collecting business requirements and analysis.
- Data Base Design.
- Coding the core modules of this product.
- Involved in bug fixing and support.
- Unit Testing.

Client: Datran Media

Period: Time Inc. Inbound/Outbound Automation **Duration:** June 08 to February 09

Role: Developer

Project Description:

To automate email Campaign deployment. This project involves the picking up client placed files from ftp location and processing them based on standard format and layout. These processed files were used for publishing campaigns, after the campaign was successfully published then generating the outbound for the files and placing them back to client location so that the client can update the error details in their database.

Tech Stack: Java and JDBC

Responsibilities:

- Participated in collecting business requirements and analysis.
- Data Base Design.
- Coding the core modules of this product.
- Involved in bug fixing and support.
- Unit Testing.

Client: Time Inc., Amex, HBG

Project Name: CCR Tool Duration: August 07 to June 08

Role: Developer

Project Description:

This tool helps customers track every metrics of a deployed email campaign. Email campaigns metrics such as scheduled, delivered, domain wise opens, clicks abuse and unsubscribes tracking were included. It involved fetching campaign specific responses from various database and update them into a common location. These responses were displayed in the tool.

Tech Stack: Java, JDBC, PHP, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Shell scripting

Responsibilities:

- Participated in collecting business requirements and analysis.
- Data Base Design.
- Coding the core modules of this product.
- Unit Testing.
- Involved in bug fixing.

Client: Time Inc., Century 21, Sony Pictures, Datran Media, American Express